Luke Stilson

Technical Artist

Contact Information:

• **Phone:** 779-537-0794

• Email: stilson.luke@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/luke-stilson
 Portfolio / Personal Site: www.lukestilson.com

Summary:

Technical Artist with extensive experience in custom tools creation for studio art workflows, shader creation, optimization, game development, and pipeline creation. Adept at bridging the gap between artists and programmers with a strong focus on asset prep and delivery, particle systems, game art optimization, rendering, animation, shader design, and sound design.

Top Skills:

- Tools design for game art Python, C#, C++, Blender geometry nodes, Unreal blueprints
- Shader design and integration Substance, Shadergraph, node-based shaders, openGL
- Asset prep and optimization pipeline tools, animation setup, gameplay prototyping

Experience:

OnChain Studios

Technical Artist

February 2023 - Present

- Asset prep and delivery optimization for Unity
- Unity asset pipeline creation using OpenPype and Ayon
- Animation controller design and integration
- Shader design and optimization using Substance Designer and ShaderGraph
- Gameplay and real-time cinematic development and rendering
- VFX design and integration

Arrow International, Inc.

Lead Technical Artist August 2020 - February 2023

- Bridged the gap between artists and programmers, leading meetings on structure, pipeline, and organization
- Converted art assets into game-ready assets, compositing EXR files, prepping rigged models, and creating scene layouts using Blender, Maya, Substance, and Adobe tools for Unity
- Developed and documented tools for artists and programmers to improve workflow, including Blender Python addons, Unity C# scripts, and GLSL & node-based shaders
- Prepared and implemented shaders, scene layouts, and gameplay interactions using Animation Controllers and C#

ONEFIRE, Inc.

3D Generalist, Gameplay Programmer
July 2017 - January 2020 (on contract basis)

- Pitch, design, and develop advertising games from start to finish using Unreal Engine
- Designed props, game-ready materials, shaders and UI for Unity and Unreal Engine
- Created 2D and 3D content for mobile, AR and VR games
- Created digital music and sound effects for games

Float

Designer

July 2017 - February 2018

- Created 2D, 3D, and Vector graphic elements for mobile learning applications
- Designed UI for high-profile client websites and apps
- Assisted in establishing ideal user flow with regards to UI/UX using flow charts
- Managed content with CMS tools and GitHub

The Iona Group

Animator / Front-End Developer
July 2017 - February 2018

- Created branded informative animations for various clients
- Designed and pitched detailed storyboarded animations to clients
- Developed atomic web elements using Twig, SCSS and JavaScript

Education:

Bradley University

Bachelor of Science in Game and Interactive Media Design, Music 2013 - 2017